Hi and welcome back. Here's my solution for this model that uses a LogSoftmax output.
欢迎回来下面介绍如何创建使用 LogSoftmax 输出的模型
It is a pretty similar to what I built before with an index sequential.
和之前使用 nn.sequential 创建的模型很像
So, we just use a linear transformation,
网络层级是线性转换、
ReLU, linear transformation, ReLU,
ReLU、线性转换 、ReLU、
another linear transformation for output and then we can pass this
线性转换
to our LogSoftmax module.
然后将这个传入 LogSoftmax 模块
So, what I'm doing here is I'm making sure I set
要注意
the dimension to one for LogSoftmax and this
将 LogSoftmax 里的维度设为 1
makes it so that it calculates the function across the columns instead of the rows.
它就会针对列计算结果 而不是行
So, if you remember, the rows correspond to our examples.
行对应的是样本
So, we have a batch of examples that we're passing
我们将一批样本传入网络中
to our network and each row is one of those examples.
每行都是一个样本
So, we want to make sure that we're covering
要注意
the softmax function across each of our examples and
对每个样本计算 softmax 函数
not across each individual feature in our batches.
而不是针对批次中的每个特征计算该函数
Here, I'm just defining our loss or criterion as
在这里将损失/条件
the negative log likelihood loss and
定义为负对数似然损失
again get our images and labels from our train loader,
从 trainloader 获取图像和标签
flatten them, pass it through our model to get the logits.
扁平化图像 传入模型中以获得对数
So, this is actually not the largest anymore,
这里不再是对数
this is like a log probability,
而是对数概率
so we call it like logps,
称为 logps
and then you do that.
这里也更改下
There you go. You see we get our nice loss.
好了我们计算出了损失
Now, we know how to calculate a loss,
现在我们知道如何计算损失了
but how do we actually use it to perform backpropagation?
但是如何用损失进行反向传播呢？
So, PyTorch towards actually has this really great module called
PyTorch 提供了一个非常有用的模块 叫做 Autograd
Autograd that automatically calculates the gradients of our tensors.
它可以自动计算张量的梯度
So, the way it works is that,
它的工作原理是
PyTorch will keep track of all the operations you do on
PyTorch 将跟踪你对张量执行的所有操作
a tensor and then when you can tell it to do a backwards pass,
然后你可以告诉它进行反向传播
to go backwards through each of
反向执行每个操作
those operations and calculate the gradients with respect to the input parameters.
并计算相对于输入参数的梯度
In general, you need to tell PyTorch that you want to use autograd on a specific tensor.
你需要告诉 PyTorch 你想对特定的张量使用 autograd
So, in this case, you would create some tensor like x equals torch.zeros,
例如 创建一个张量 x = torch.zeros
just to make it a scalar,
将其设为标量 例如 1
say one and then give it requires grad equals true.
然后设置为 requires_grad = True
So, this tells PyTorch to track the operations on this tensor x,
这部分告诉 PyTorch 跟踪对张量 x 执行的操作
so that if you want to get the gradient then it will calculate it for you.
如果你想获得梯度 它将为你计算梯度
So, in general, if you're creating a tensor and
如果你创建了一个张量
you don't want to calculate the gradient for it,
但是不想计算它的梯度
you want to make sure this is set to false.
则将这个设为 False
You can also use this context torch.no grad to make sure
还可以使用 torch.no_grad
all the gradients are shut off for all of
对在这个上下文中执行的所有操作
the operations that you're doing while you're in this context.
关闭所有梯度
Then, you can also turn on or off gradients globally with
还可以使用 torch.set_grad_enabled
torch.set grad enabled and give it true or false, depending on what you want to do.
全局性地开启或关闭所有梯度 在这里设置 true 或 false 即可
So, the way this works in PyTorch is that you basically create your tensor and again,
我们在 PyTorch 中创建张量
you set requires grad equals true and then you just perform some operations on it.
设置 requires_grad = True 然后对该张量执行操作
Then, once you are done with those operations, you type in.backwards.
操作完毕后 输入 .backwards
So, if you use x, this tensor x,
如果使用张量 x
then calculate some other tensor z then if you do z.backward,
然后计算出其他张量 z 执行 z.backward
it'll go backwards through your operations and calculate the total gradient for x.
它将反向经过操作并计算 x 的总梯度
So, for example, if I just create this random tensor,
例如 我创建了这个随机张量
random two-by-two tensor, and then I can square it like this.
随机的 2x2 张量 像这样变成方形
What it does, you can actually see if you look at y,
如果你查看 y
so y is our secondary or squared tensor.
y 是第二个方形张量
If you look at y.grad function,
如果查看 y.grad_fn
then it actually shows us that this grad function is a power.
它会显示这个 grad 函数是一个幂
So, PyTorch just track this and it
PyTorch 跟踪了这个操作
knows that the last operation done was a power operation.
知道最后一个操作是幂运算
So, now, we can take the mean of y and get another tensor z.
现在我们可以对 y 取均值并获得另一个张量 z
So, now this is just a scalar tensor, we've reduced y,
这是一个标量张量 我们缩减了 y
y is a two-by-two matrix,
y 是一个 2 x 2 矩阵/数组
two by two array and then we take in the mean of it to get z.
然后对其取均值 得出 z
Ingredients for tensor show up in this attribute grad,
张量的梯度显示在属性 grad 中
so we can actually look at what's the gradient of our tensor x right now,
现在我们可以查看张量 x 的梯度
and we've only done this forward pass,
我们仅进行了前向传播
we haven't actually calculated the gradient yet and so it's just none.
尚未计算梯度 因此为 None
So, now if we do z.backward,
现在如果执行 z.backward
it's going to go backwards through this tiny little set of operations that we've done.
它将反向经过我们执行的这小部分操作
So, we did a power and then a mean and let's go
我们进行了幂运算和取均值运算
backwards through this and calculate the gradient for x.
我们反向传播并计算 x 的梯度
So, if you actually work out the math,
结果你会发现
you find out that the gradient of z with respect to x should
z 相对于 x 的梯度应该是 x/2
be x over two and if we look at the gradient,
查看梯度
then we can also look at x divided by two then they are the same.
看看 x/2 它们是一样的
So, our gradient is equal to what it should be mathematically,
从数学角度来看 梯度等于预期结果
and this is the general process for working with gradients,
这就是在 autograd 和 PyTorch 中
and autograd, and PyTorch.
使用梯度的一般流程
Why this is useful,
在计算损失时 我们可以使用它计算梯度
is because we can use this to get our gradients when we calculate the loss.
很有用 对不对
So, if remember, our loss depends on our weight and bias parameters.
损失取决于权重和偏差参数
We need the gradients of our weights to do gradient descent.
我们需要权重梯度来执行梯度下降法
So, what we can do is we can set up our weights as
我们可以将权重设为需要梯度的张量
tensors that require gradients and then do a forward pass to calculate our loss.
然后进行前向传播以计算损失
With the loss, you do a backwards pass which calculates the gradients for your weights,
获得损失后 进行反向传播以计算权重的梯度
and then with those gradients, you can do your gradient descent step.
获得这些梯度后 可以执行梯度下降步骤
Now, I'll show you how that looks in code.
我来演示下代码
So, here, I'm defining our model like I did before with LogSoftmax output,
像之前一样定义模型 这里是 LogSoftmax 输出
then using the negative log-likelihood loss,
使用负对数似然损失
get our images and labels from our train loader, flatten it,
从 trainloader 中获取图像和标签 扁平化图像
and then we can get our log probabilities from
然后从模型中获得对数概率
our model and then pass that into our criterion,
传入损失函数里
which gives us the actual loss.
获得实际损失
So, now, if we look at our models weights,
现在查看模型权重
so model zero gives us the parameters for this first linear transformation.
Model[0] 对应的是第一个线性转换的参数
So, we can look at the weight and then we can look at the gradient,
查看权重梯度
then we'll do our backwards pass starting from
然后从损失开始进行反向传播
the loss and then we can look at the weight gradients again.
再次查看权重梯度
So, we see before the backward pass,
在反向传播之前
we don't have any because we haven't actually
没有任何梯度 这是因为我们尚未计算它
calculated it yet but then after the backwards pass,
但是在反向传播之后
we have calculated our gradients.
我们计算了梯度
So, we can use these gradients in gradient descent to train our network. All right.
我们可以在梯度下降步骤中使用这些梯度训练网络
So, now you know how to calculate losses and you know
现在你知道如何计算损失
how to use those losses to calculate gradients.
如何使用这些损失计算梯度
So, there's one piece left before we can start training.
但是在开始训练之前 还有一步
So, you need to see how to use those gradients to actually update our weights,
你需要知道如何使用这些梯度更新权重
and for that we use optimizers and these come from PyTorch's Optim package.
接下来 我们将使用优化器 优化器来自 PyTorch 的 optim 软件包
So, for example, we can use stochastic gradient descent with optim.SGD.
例如 我们可以通过输入 optim.SGD 使用随机梯度下降法
The way this is defined is we import
定义方式是
this module optim from PyTorch and then we'd say optim.SGD,
从 PyTorch 导入模块 optim 在这里输入 optim.SGD
we give it our model parameters.
传入模型参数
So, these are the parameters that we want
这些是我们希望优化器更新的参数
this optimizer to actually update and then we give it a learning rate,
然后设定学习速率
and this creates our optimizer for us.
这样就创建了优化器
So, the training pass consists of four different steps.
训练流程包含四个不同的步骤
So, first, we're going to make a forward pass through the network
首先对网络进行前向传播
then we're going to use that network output to calculate the loss,
然后使用该网络输出计算损失
then we'll perform a backwards pass through
使用 loss.backwards
the network with loss.backwards and this will calculate the gradients.
对网络进行反向传播并计算梯度
Then, we'll make a step with our optimizer that updates the weights.
然后使用优化器更新权重
I'll show you how this works with one training step and then you're going
我在这里只演示训练一步
to write it up for real and a loop that is going to train a network.
然后你将编写实际训练过程 循环地训练网络
So, first, we're going to start by getting our images
首先
and labels like we normally do from
从 trainloader 获取图像和标签
our train loader and then we're going to flatten them.
然后扁平化图像
Then next, what we want to do is actually clear the gradients.
接下来清理梯度
So, PyTorch by default accumulates gradients.
PyTorch 默认地会累积梯度
That means that if you actually do
如果你在网络中传播多次
multiple passes and multiple backwards like multiple forward passes,
即 多次执行前向传播和反向传播
multiple backwards passes, and you keep calculating your gradient,
并不断计算梯度
it's going to keep summing up those gradients.
PyTorch 将不断将这些梯度加起来
So, if you don't clear gradients,
如果不清理梯度
then you're going to be getting gradients from the previous training step in
那么在当前训练中
your current training step and it's going to end up where
会残留上个训练步骤的梯度
your network is just not training properly.
导致网络无法正常训练
So, for this in general,
因此在每个训练流程之前
you're going to be calling zero grad before every training passes.
你需要调用 zero_grad()
So, you just say optimizer.zero grad and this will just clean
输入 optimizer.zero_grad
out all the gradients and all the parameters in your optimizer,
它会在优化器里清理所有参数中的所有梯度
and it'll allow you to train appropriately.
让我们能够正常训练网络
So, this is one of the things in PyTorch that is easy to forget,
这点很容易被忽略
but it's really important.
但是这一步很重要
So, try your hardest to remember to do this part,
请务必记住
and then we do our forward pass,
接着 执行前向传播和反向传播
backward pass, then update the weights.
并更新权重
So, we get our output,
获得输出
so we do a forward pass through our model with our images,
使用图像对模型进行前向传播
then we calculate the loss using the output of the model and our labels,
使用模型的输出和标签计算损失
then we do a backwards pass and then finally we take an optimizer step.
然后反向传播 最后执行优化器步骤
So, if we look at our initial weights,
这是初始权重
so it looks like this and then we can calculate our gradient,
然后计算梯度
and so the gradient looks like and then if
梯度是这样的
we take an optimizer step and update our weights,
然后执行优化器步骤并更新权重
then our weights have changed.
权重更改了
So, in general, what has worked is you're going to be looping
你将遍历训练集
through your training set and then for each batch out of your training set,
对于训练集中的每批数据
you'll do the same training pass.
你将执行相同的训练流程
So, you'll get your data,
获取数据
then clear the gradients,
清理梯度
pass those images or your input through your network to get your output, from that,
将图像/输入传入网络中 获得输出
in the labels, calculate your loss,
使用标签计算损失
and then do a backwards pass on the loss and then update your weights.
然后用损失反向传播并更新权重
So, now, it's your turn to implement the training loop for this model.
现在该你来为此模型实现训练循环了
So, the idea here is that we're going to be looping through our data-set,
你要将遍历数据集
so grabbing images and labels from train loader and then on each of those batches,
从 trainloader 中获取图像和标签
you'll be doing the training pass,
然后对每批数据执行训练流程
and so you'll do this pass where you calculate the output of the network,
计算网络输出
calculate the loss, do backwards pass on loss,
计算损失 对损失进行反向传播
and then update your weights.
然后更新权重
Each pass through the entire training set is called an
经过整个数据集 1 次称为 1 个周期
epoch and so here I just have it set for five epochs.
我将周期设成了 5 次
So, you can change this number if you want to go more or less.
当然 你也可以改为其他次数
Once you calculate the loss,
计算损失后
we can accumulate it to keep track,
我们可以递增这个值以进行跟踪
so we're going to be looking at a loss.
最后就能查看损失
So, this is running loss and so we'll be
调用 running_loss
printing out the training loss as it's going along.
输出训练损失
So, if it's working,
当你继续使用数据训练网络时
you should see the loss start falling,
如果操作正确的话
start dropping as you're going through the data.
应该看到损失开始降低
Try this out yourself and if you need some help,
自己尝试一下吧
be sure to check out my solution. Cheers.
如果需要帮助 请参阅我的解决方案加油！